Elias Toscano Manzano

Charlotte N.C. 29815

980-402-3211

etoscanoprime@gmail.com

LinkedIn profile

RESUME SUMMARY:

IT professional with over three years of experience in developing Enterprise-based Client-Server business applications with Angular, React, Spring Boot, HTML5, CSS3 as well as plain Javascript within agile frameworks. Dedicated to delivering high-quality solutions, optimizing performance, and ensuring smooth front-end and back-end integrations and communication.

EXPERIENCE:

FRONT END DEVELOPER | INTEGRASS | JULY 2022 - CURRENT

- Developed application for managing global merchandise containers, providing real-time tracking for clients.
- Leveraged ag-Grid and highcharts libraries to create an interactive dashboard for data visualization.
- Implement a custom chakra theme on OOTB and custom components.
- Ensured the application compatibility across different browsers and devices, enhancing user accessibility.
- Worked closely with the backend team to ensure seamless integration of FE component with BE logic.
- Implementing functionality in existing codebases using Typescript and JavaScript.
- Migrated application from Angular to React, ensuring seamless functionality and enhanced user experience.
- Translating feedback into application improvements to and code enhancements
- Led initiatives to improve code quality, performance, and maintainability through code reviews, refactoring
 and implementation of design patters.
- Worked in an agile environment with daily stand-ups and technical refinements and used Agile practices to determine solutions to technical problems.
- Authored and modified YAML files in the backend project to define page structure and grid column specifications.

FRONT END DEVELOPER - ENTRY LEVEL | INTEGRASS | JUNE 2021 - JULY 2022

- Integrated new widgets into the app using the client's Angular component-based library.
- Utilized the client products for implementing authentication and authorization portals.
- Agile development processes, sprint planning, daily stand-ups, sprint reviews, and retrospective.
- Proactively identified potential risks and devised effective strategies to mitigate them.
- Worked closely with the UI/UX team updating themes, managing media resources.
- Backend integration to register new users, recover passwords and limit registration attempts.
- Improved user experience by implementing client's latest requirements closely working with QA team.
- Migrated legacy client website to a modern looking website, ensuring all functionality regarding accessibility was kept intact.
- Assist code reviews and provided constructive feedback to team members to ensure adherence to SOLID principles.
- Implemented UI designs and mockups provided, ensuring pixel-perfect accuracy and responsiveness.
- Successfully completed the app within a short timeframe, gaining insight into the criticality of seemingly trivial
 cases.
- Developed web app for Banco Nacional de Peru to facilitate stimulus payments during the pandemic, focusing
 on inclusivity and accessibility for users without formal banking access.

INTERN (HTML, CSS, JS & ANGULAR) | INTEGRASS | JANUARY 2021 – JUNE 2021

- Developed an internal website using HTML, CSS, typescript on Angular.
- Identified and fix bugs and issues in existing web applications, ensuring optimal functionality and performance.
- Acquired hands-on experience in an Agile workflow.
- Actively participate in code reviews, providing feedback on peers code and learning others styles and techniques.
- Contributed on developing new features, enhancements for live applications, following client's standard.
- Developed technical requirements and features using user stories, while tracking progress and challenges.
- Collaborated with other team members, including designers, BE developers to deliver on the estimated deadlines.
- Engaged in daily stand-up meetings and reviewed tasks using tools such as Jira and Confluence.
- Managed multiple project tickets effectively, always delivering before deadlines.
- Continuously having my code subjected to review by senior developers to ensure best practices.

EDUCATION

APRIL 6 2021

JS ALGORITHMS AND DATA STRUCTURES | FREE CODE CAMP

APRIL 21 2021

RESPONSIVE WEB DESIGN | FREE CODE CAMP

OCTOBER 2023

ORACLE NEXT EDUCATION PROGRAM - BACK-END

ORACLE - JAVA AND SPRING BOOT - CHECK HERE

ORACLE - INTEGRATE JAVA APPS WITH DB - CHECK HERE

ORACLE - OOP TRAINING - CHECK HERE

SKILLS & PREFERRED TOOLS

- Development, libraries & frameworks: Angular, React, Spring Boot, HTML5, CSS, Sass, Javascript (plain and Typescript), Chakra UI, Bootstrap, Angular Material, Figma, Visual Studio Code, IntelliJ IDEA, Postman, high-charts.
- Environment: Mac OS.
- Project Management: Agile Methodologies.
- Quality assurance: Code reviews, debugging, QA collaboration.
- Problem solving: identifying risks, implementing effective strategies, adhering to SOLID principles.